Abdul Kyume

Software Engineer



in abdul-kyume (abdulkyume

Jatrabari, Dhaka

ABOUT ME

Versatile Software Engineer with 1.5 year experience, specializing in front-end technology while adeptly navigating backend development. Committed to delivering captivating and seamless user experiences, I bring innovation, adaptability, and strong problem-solving skills to every project. A collaborative communicator with a passion for staying at the forefront of technological advancements. Ready to make a positive impact in the digital world.

EDUCATION

BSc. in Computer Science and Engineering

East West University 🗷

2018 - 2022

CGPA: 3.49

THESIS

Contextual Bangla Next Word Prediction Using Bi-directional RNN with Attention Mechanism NLP, Deep Learning, Python

COURSES

Quantum Method Course 🗷

Quantum Foundation

Jan 2013 – Jan 2013 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Mind Development and Self-Improvement Course

Complete Web Design by SEIP

BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM) Jan 2022 - Apr 2022 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trust Axiata Digital Limited

Software Engineer

Jan 2023 – present

Qunatum Foundation (Volunteer) 🗷

Web Application Developer

Oct 2022 - present

SKILLS

Programming Skills

C, C++, Python, Java, Javascript

Front-End Development

HTML, CSS, SCSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Typescript, Angular, React

Back-End Development

RESTful API, ExpresJs, NodeJS, Java, Spring Boot 3, PHP, .NET

Database

MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase

Other Tools

Figma, Github, GitLab, VScode, MS Office Package

PROJECTS

Admin Portal for TADL (ongoing)

Developed using Angular

Helped to build some APIs in Dot Net. Integrated APIs with Portal.

Portal for Trust Axiata Pay merchant (ongoing)

Build using Angular

Rich Text Editor (Ongoing) ☑

Angular

Supports Firefox Browser Only

Live Link - https://myeditor.stackblitz.io

Khoshgolpo 🛮

A Communication App using Angular, Firebase

Trust Axiata Pay Corporate Website 🖸

Build with WordPress, Elementor

Push Notification Scheduler Service

Build using Spring Boot 3

Prescription Management System

using html,css,bootstrap,php,mysql Github Link -

https://github.com/abdulkyume/prescriptionmanagement-system

Applicantor Website Template 🗵

build with html,css,bootstap,javascript,jquery Live Link - https://abdulkyume.github.io/Applicantor/

Ulence Website Template

build with html,css,bootstap,javascript,jquery

♠ ORGANIZATIONS

Ouantum Foundation

Volunteer

Volunteer at Jatrabari Branch

★ INTEREST

Gaming, Food, Travelling

REFERENCES

Zubair Khaled, Assistant Vice President, HSBC zubair.khaled@hsbc.com.bd, 01730387705